Inventory of the Austin-Twyman Papers, 1765-1939
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Letters, 1765-1939. (Folder 1-159)
  - Letters to, from, or about the Twyman Family, 1811-1937, n.d. (Folder 22-125)
    - Iverson L. Twyman, 1829-1864., 513 items. (Folder 22-50)
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), 1846., 17 items. (Folder 36)
        Includes letters from B. M. DeWitt, F. Hopkins, Jessie T. Agee, J. B. Reswick & Co., David B. Phelps, S. C. Banks, H. Mongomerie, Julia DeWitt, Francis T. Stribling (superintendent of Western Asylum), G. T. Thornton. Letters concern hiring of slaves.
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), 1847., 14 items. (Folder 37)
        Includes letters from Geo. T. Thornton (concerning his courtship), B. M. DeWitt (concerning his financial condition), Martha M. Phillips, P[aulus] Powell ([1809-1874] Congressman), James Alexander, D. T. C. Peters, V. Mosby.
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), 1848., 18 items. (Folder 38)
        Includes letters from B. M. DeWitt (concerning George T. Thornton; and the Richmond Examiner), V. P. Mosby, John G. McClanahan, Daniel P. Woodson, James M. Harris, S. P. [Vauter ?], D. P. Gooch, Seth Woodruff (evaluating slaves), W. A. Payne, Charles Scott (by Robert Pleasants), Anthony Thornton.
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), 1849., 18 items. (Folder 39)
        Includes letters from George T. Thornton (concerning Paulus Powell), James Brown (concerning a slavetrader, Samuel Rees), James M. Harris, E. Wingfield, D. P. Gooch, W. A. Payne (concerning possibility of gonorrhea among slaves), Andrew White, D. C. Jones, W. T. Young, Frances Rogers, E. Franklin, Jr. William H. Brown.
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), 1850., 16 items. (Folder 40)
        Includes letters from DeWitt H. White (concerning his medical practice), R. B. Gooch (concerning The Southern Planter), W. C. Jordan (granting permission for his slave to marry one of Twyman's slaves if Twyman approves), [Meem ?] Gwatkin, Thomas Robert, Anthony Thornton (concerning George Thornton), David S. Kaufman (describing Texas), Daniel Woodson (concerning Texas), R. D. Palmer, unidentified writer (concerning candidates for Convention for 1850; and poisoning by slaves), Bennitt M. DeWitt (concerning Richmond Examiner), E. A. Palmer, J. B. Strong (concerning hiring slaves).
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), 1851., 10 items. (Folder 41)
        Includes letters from Robert A. Stephens (concerning hiring slaves), William M. Blackford, [?] Hopkins, Daniel Woodson (concerning east-west plit of Virginia), Benjamin Winter, Ritchie & Dunnavant, R. Strabler & Co.
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), 1852., 13 items. (Folder 42)
        Includes letters from James D. Watts (asking Twyman to act as a protector and advisor to Watt's slave), R. C. Woody, Nathaniel Woodhouse, F. M. Cabell, L. Brown, Zullock & Crenshaw, Seth Woodruff (asking for slave to be delivered so she can be sent south with others), William N. Chick, William M. Cabell, J. W. Cameron, Mary M. Cameron.
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), 1853., 15 items. (Folder 43)
        Includes letters from H. Mundy (his medical studies at University of Virginia; and death of John Austin), Smith Bosworth, L H. Wingfield, B. M. DeWitt (concerning family rift; and editing newspaper in Alabama), Thomas A Carter (punishment of slave), Silas P. Vauter, Joseph Kyle, R. W. Shaw (hiring slave), George T. Thornton, John F. White, B. Gildersleeve, Jackson L. Thornton (concerning George T. Thornton), James M. [Fulks ?], Jno. F. Hix (hiring slaves).
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), 1854., 15 items. (Folder 44)
        Includes letters from J. B. Scott (illness of slave), Smith Bosworth (hiring slave), John C. Mundy (medical studies at University of Pennsylvania), James E. Horner (hiring slave), W. H. Perkins (meeting of General Assembly), Samuel Scott, J. B. Wilkinson (hiring slaves), Jefferson Mays, George T. Thornton (his medical practice), Jesse L. Wilkinson, Benjamin S. Vawter (his medical studies at University of Virginia), R. H. Dickinson & Brother (evaluation of slaves), Jno. S. Cocke, Robert H. Gray (hiring slaves to work on Virginia & Tennessee Railroad).
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), 1855., 30 items. (Folder 45)
        Includes letters from A. M. Montgomery (hiring slaves to lay railroad track), Dickinson, Hill & Co. (value of slaves), Pulliam & Davis (value of slaves), James D. Watts (illness of slaves), George G. Curle (hiring of slaves), Jno. W. Haskins, M. F. Perkins (hiring overseer), L. H. Wingfield, George T. Thornton, James M. Cunningham (his illness), Walter S. Dunn ([of James River and Kanawha Canal]; runaway hired slaved), Francis A. Blu[?], W. P. Hill (appointing Twyman delegate for Medical Society of Virginia to National Medical Association in Philadelphia), William M. Cabell, George B. Thurman, B. M. DeWitt, J. C. Mundy, James B. Hargrove, L. H. Wingfield, A. N. Montgomery, W. T. Anderson, L. P. Mercer, James M. Fulks, Smith Bosworth.
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), 1856-1858., 34 items. (Folder 46)
        Includes letters from J. C. Mundy, Taliaferro & Hamilton, S. F. Lucado, N. F. Bocock (runaway slave), B. M. DeWitt, James M. Harris (hire of slaves; runaway hired slave), J. D. Damson, Lewis H. Wingfield, A. Hopkins, Charles R. Shepard, H. Wilson Hix (hire of slave), Lawson G. Tyler (sending slave nurse), John Harry (his illness), James Bolton (treatment of injured eye), David R. Lew, Isaac Hays (treatment of injured eye), Adie Gray, Th. F. Perkins, Eliza Spencer, Mary Miller, D. M. Pulliam & Co. (sale of runaway slave), James M. Fulks (hire of slave), S. J. Woolridge, Elizabeth A. Harvey, Mayo Cabell, R. T. Ellis, Jr., William J. Spencer (overseer of the poor, Buckingham Co., Va.), William D. Cabell (hire of slave and his treatment.)
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), 1859-1860., 35 items. (Folder 47)
        Includes letters from Absalom (slave letter), W. Gill (concerning slave Absalom), James M. Harris (hiring slaves for James River and Kanawha Canal), Robert A. Banks (politics), L. D. Mercer, R. H. Gilliam, Doctor James Bolton, Jordan Taylor (health of slave), D. H. Landon, J. Lawrence Meem, Alfred Iverson (concerning geneology of Iverson family), J. L. Thornton (illness and death of George T. Thornton), M. G. C. Long, W. M. Woodward, Adeline A. Sands (applying for teaching position), E. J. Snow (her firing as teacher), D. A. Snow (for A. Snow concerning firing of E. J. Snow), Hableston & Bro., T. Lyon, A. M. Ford(applying for teaching position), Mary F. Dandridge, John G. Meem, M. E. Walsh (negotiating and accepting teaching position), Lucy C. Bondurant (applying for teaching position), E. H. Gill (hiring slaves for Virginia and Tennessee Railroad), Ada B. Bocock.
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), 1861-1864., 42 items. (Folder 48)
        Includes letters from B. M. DeWitt, W. P. Mosley (candidate for Secession Convention), McCorkle & Co. (hiring slaves), E. H. Gill (hiring slaves for Virginia and Tennessee Railroad), unidentified writer (hiring of slaves), Ella T. Watson (her education), C. Emma Moore, James M. Harris, Lucy C. Bondurant, William Knabe & Co. (piano), John G. Meem, Conrad Freimann (piano), Peter R. Patterson, C. A. Preots ([Buckingham] F[emale] C[ollegiate] Institute), James L. Stephens, Robert [Keats ?], L. D. Jones, T. T. Omohundro, E. H. Gill, R. H. Gillam, John Farriss (hiring slaves), Elsom Bro. & Co., Howardsville, Va., Jacob Garrett, H. M. Bondurant, Robert L. Ragland, John H. Bondurant (hiring slaves), Judith B. Smith, Charles R. Ackerly, Z. G. Wood, Sarah S.. Carnifer, Wilson Hix (to Martha (Austin) Twyman), Thomas P. Childress, Mary Clegg (applying for teaching position), R. S. Powers.
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), 1863-1864., 35 items. (Folder 49)
        Includes letters by Thomas Dodermead (hiring slaves for Virginia and Tennessee Railroad Co.; runaway hired hand, Beverly); "A Methodist" (concerning a teaching position; she studied at Buckingham Female Collegiate Institute), W. A. Turner (hiring slaves), Jno. J. Riggins (teaching), Bocock & Parrish, John W. Wingfield (paymaster for Virginia and Tennessee Railroad, hiring slaves), Mary [Annis?] DeWitt (illness of B. M. DeWitt, bears letter of J. C. Mundy), Jno. F Hix (death of B. M. DeWitt), Mary A. Morris (requesting that her husband be re-committed to Western State Asylum), R. B. Shaw, Jr. (speculating that Lee may attack Hooker), Samuel Read (Confederate government's hiring of slaves), J. A. Hefelfinger (Coyner's Springs), Adeline A. Sands (teaching position), Hetty R. Gillam, N. F. Bocock, Stabler & Jones, C. Amanda Hix, J. L. Thornton (describing Union raid in Orange County, Va.), Robert Atkinson, Hill, Dickinson & Co., Richmond, Va. (price of slaves), R. P. Pattison, W. W. Forbes (hiring slaves for Joseph R. Anderson & Co. [Tredegar]), Brown & Deane, Richmond, Va. (scarcity of schoolbooks) E. A. Cabell, Thomas F. Perkins (school), Julia E. DeWitt, W. M. Jerdone (his school), Alfred Hughes, A. Brooks (Confederate cavalryman from Georgia).
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), n.d., 36 items. (Folder 50)
        Includes letters by George T. Thornton, J. M. Harris, Jno. F. Hix, Cambridge Austin (slave letter), James Jones, Ths. M. Watson, E. A. Cabell (hiring slaves), Mrs. E. H. Gill, L. D. Jones, Th[omas] Wilson Hix, V. P. Mosby, Francis A. Blair, R. S. Ellis, Jr., Benjamin F. Rodes, E. H. Gill, William D. Hix, E. D. Moore, Jesse A. Watts (at the University of Virginia), Bennitt M. DeWitt (family rift), George W. Clark, O. A. (speech by Governor Barbour), W. C. Jordan (describing how to build a hot bed to grow potatoes), M. F. [Perkins ?], Doctor James Bolton (from Twyman), P[aulus] Powell, Hiram C. Kyle, [?] Austin, L. W. Cabell.
    - Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, 1848-1891, n.d., 218 items. (Folder 51-64)
      - Letters by Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, 1848., 7 items. (Folder 51)
        Includes letters to Frances Austin Wright (mother's female illness; an alleged malingering and burglarizing female slave; fixing new clothes to sell a slave in; sewing slave clothing; selling of slaves), John Austin (fixing up slaves to sell), mother Grace R. Austin (having teeth fixed - bears letter of Iverson Lewis Twyman to George B. Austin).
      - Letters by Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, 1849-1850., 7 items. (Folder 52)
        Includes letters to sister Grace Austin, Frances Austin (family rift), John Austin, Iverson L. Twyman.
      - Letters by Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, 1851-1869., 16 items. (Folder 53)
        Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (letter, 13 September 1853 bears letter of Frances A. Austin concerning slave leaving to visit his wife). Other letters concern dressing slaves up to sell them and slave Beverly apparently with Confederate Army during Gettysburg Campaign), James M. Spiller, R. S. Ellis, Jr. (to Martha Twyman), J. Avis Bartley and Sarah F. Harris.
      - Letters by Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, 1870-1871., 25 items. (Folder 54)
        Includes letters to her son Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), concerning her worry about him, the education of his brothers and sisters, an umber mine on her farm, and sharecropping with freed blacks. Includes a letter to James A. Wright and one letter from Mabel Twyman to her brother Iverson Twyman.
      - Letters by Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, 1872., 27 items. (Folder 55)
        Written to her son Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921). Concerns the family's poverty and her concern over the sale of family land. Includes a letter to Mary Spiller and a letter from Mabel B. Twyman. Includes a draft of a letter to C. L. Cocke concerning Hollins Institute.
      - Letters by Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, 1873., 16 items. (Folder 56)
        Written to her son Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921). Concerns the family's poverty and her concern over the sale of family land. Includes a letter to Mary Spiller.
      - Letters by Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, 1874., 16 items. (Folder 57)
        Concerns the family's poverty and money owed to West & Agee which may force the sale of her land.
      - Letters by Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, 1875-1877., 17 items. (Folder 58)
        Written to her son Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921). Concern the family's poverty and her concern over her son's safety.
      - Letters by Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, 1878-1879., 10 items. (Folder 59)
        Written to her son Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921). Concern the family's poverty and her concern for her son.
      - Letters by Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, 1880-1890., 13 items. (Folder 60)
        Written to her son John Twyman. Includes letters to John Twyman from Sam Twyman, Iverson L. Twyman and Augusta G. Twyman and a letter of Martha E. (Austin) Twyman to Iverson L. Twyman.
      - Letters by Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, n.d., 6 items. (Folder 61)
        Written to Iverson L Twyman (1810-1864). Frances (Austin) Wright, Nannie [?], John Austin, Iverson L. Twyman (b. 1849) and Grace Austin.
      - Letters to Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, 1849-1869., 25 items. (Folder 62)
        Includes letters from L. J. Payne, W. C. Jordan, an unidentified woman (complaining of verbal abuse by slaves), Penariah Layne, Samuel McCorkle, M. A. Robertson, Kate F. Evans, I. B. Garden (sprinkling of chloride of lime about the [slave] cabins to prevent the spread of fever), W. M. Cabell, Samuel Read (hire of slave by Confederate States Army), [James M. Spiller ?], Junius E. Leigh, James Avis Bartley, Seymour W. Holman (bears engraving of Washington College now Washington and Lee University), Internal Revenue Service (enclosing bank income tax form for 1868) and William J. Spencer.
      - Letters to Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, 1870-1891., 10 items. (Folder 63)
        Includes letters from E. A. Carter, James M. Harris, Seymour W. Holman (concerning Iverson Twyman's courtship of a Georgia woman), Charles Lewis Cocke (concerning his deduction for indigent students and his standard for hiring teachers at Hollins Institute [now Hollins College]), N. F. Ellis, [Sue Asa Washington ? - former slave ?], J. S. Tompkins (at Hollins Institute [now Hollins College] sending his treatment for typhoid fever), M. N. Cabell (concerning will of James M. Wright).
      - Letters to Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, n.d., 23 items. (Folder 64)
        Includes letters from R. S. Ellis, Jr., Nannie F. Ellis (concerning Hollins Institute [now Hollins College]), L. C. P., [John Dismuke ?], George J. Hundley, M. A. Robertson, Eliza M. Eldridge (bears draft of a letter to [?] concerning the hiring of a teacher), M. K. Cabell, Amanda [?], N. A. Moseley (concerning a slave marriage), K. M. Perkins, and Samuel B. Partin.
    - Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1861-1921., 390 items. (Folder 65-85)
      - Letters by Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1861-1871., 26 items. (Folder 65)
        Includes letters written (while teaching school in Georgia) to father Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864), mother Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, Frances A. Wright, [?] Gill (draft, 5 July 1871, of a love letter), and sister Augusta Giles Twyman.
      - Letters by Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1872., 21 items. (Folder 66)
        Includes letters written (while teaching school in Georgia, from New Orleans and while moving to Texas) to mother Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, Dan [?], Hank [Frances A. Wright], Uncle Paschal Twyman, Fannie [?], Annie [?] (love letter), James M. Spiller, M. Edwards.
      - Letters by Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1873., 19 items. (Folder 67)
        Includes letters written (while teaching school in Texas) to mother Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, Frances (Austin) Wright, Annie [?] (love letter), [?] Lowe, Augusta Giles Twyman, John Twyman.
      - Letters by Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1874., 14 items. (Folder 68)
        Includes letters written from Texas to mother Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, Frances (Austin) Wright, Annie [?], John Twyman, Alice Johnson (love letter), Letter, 14 September 1874, concerns Texas and blacks.
      - Letters by Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1875., 8 items. (Folder 69)
        Includes letters written from Texas to mother Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, Frances (Austin) Wright, John A. Twyman, Samuel R. Twyman, William Dixon, Augusta Giles Twyman.
      - Letters by Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1876., 28 items. (Folder 70)
        Includes letters written to mother Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, Augusta Giles Twyman, John A. Twyman, Samuel A. Twyman.
      - Letters by Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1877., 30 items. (Folder 71)
        Includes letters written from Texas to Augusta Giles Twyman, John Austin, Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, Hank (Frances A. Wright), Mabel Booker Twyman.
      - Letters by Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1878., 30 items. (Folder 72)
        Includes letters (written from Texas) to Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, Thomas Austin, Augusta Giles Twyman, Miss Yelverton, John A. Austin (concerning Greenback Party).
      - Letters by Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1879., 15 items. (Folder 73)
        Includes letters (written from Texas) to Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, Mabel Booker Twyman, Emma Buson, Thomas [?], Albert Langley. Last letter in folder written from Virginia.
      - Letters by Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1880., 6 items. (Folder 74)
        From Virginia to brother John in Nashville, Tennesse. One letter bears composition "Management of Common Schools" and another bears note of M. E. Twyman asking her son not to drink.
      - Letters by Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1881., 28 items. (Folder 75)
        Include letters from Virginia to brother John Twyman in Nashville (where he is attending college at State Normal College, now Peabody College) and in Texas. Two letters bear letters of Augusta Giles Twyman. Letters concern Readjuster politics in Buckingham County. "The Readjusters all over the county voted for the negro [Shed Dungee] and John Eldridge says he is prouder of that one act than of any other in his whole life." Lists other individuals who voted for Dungee. Turkey and deer hunting.
      - Letters to or about Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1882-1887., 16 items. (Folder 76)
        Letters to brother John Twyman in Texas. Concerns Mabel Booker Twyman leaving State Normal School (Peabody College) and Eben Sperry Stearns. Includes letter to Antonia (Spiller) Twyman (whom he married in 1884). Letters to Martha E. (Austin) Twyman and a letter, n.d., to J. Avis Bartley.
      - Letters to or about Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1867-1871., 5 items. (Folder 77)
        Includes letters written by Seymour W. Holman, John A. Twyman. Also includes letters from J. W. Fishburne to W. J. Moseley, B. F. Outze and J. R. Taylor concerning I. L. Twyman and Twyman's teaching certificate, 1871, issued in Meriwether County, Ga.
      - Letters to or about Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1872., 14 items. (Folder 78)
        Includes letters written by Seymour W. Holman (of Mexia, Texas), Fannie [?], Stanley P. Mosley, Addie M. Walker, W. W. Wisdom, a school agreement drawn up by Twyman and letters of recommendation written by Holman concerning Twyman's qualifications to teach school.
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1872-1874 and n.d., 25 items. (Folder 79)
        Love letters from Miss Annie Vickers (See also folders 66-68 for drafts of Twyman's letters).
      - Letters to or about Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1873., 30 items. (Folder 80)
        Includes letters from J. L. Lowe, Seymour W. Holman, W. P. Moseley, Mary P. Moreland, Gussie Moreland, W. H. Richardson (to George J. Hundley concerning appointment of John A Twyman to VMI), P. H. Dunson, J. P. Philpott, Wilson, Hinkle & Co., Cincinnati, Ohio (concerning schoolbooks), Hattie Harris, A. M. Johnson, Maggie Harris, A. M. Johnson, L. D. Forbes. Letters concern Mexia, Texas and teaching school.
      - Letters to or about Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1874., 15 items. (Folder 81)
        Includes letters from W. M. Thornton, George J. Hundley, John M. Colby, J. W. Fishburne, M. Washington, C. F. Scott. Letters concern teaching school.
      - Letters to or about Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1876-1877., 20 items. (Folder 82)
        Includes letters from R. F. Mills, Jno. T. Blalock, Thomas F. Lewis, Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, W. B. Blalock, W. L. Price, and letters concerning Twyman's church membership and letters of recommendation. Includes a teaching certificate for Limestone, Texas.
      - Letters to or about Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1878., 24 items. (Folder 83)
        Includes letters from Seymour W. Holman, (letter, 8 May 1878, concerns lynching of a black), W. P. Moseley, Rush G. Kimball, James B. Thurman, Thomas Waters, S. P. Moseley, Fanny Prendergast, Laura Rogers. Letters concern Mexia, Texas and teaching school.
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1879., 12 items. (Folder 84)
        Includes letters from M. E. Robertson, H. Beall, Albert Langley, C. P. Estill, Jno. F. Blalock, R[ush] G. Kimball, Henry L. Holman. Letters concern Mexia, Texas and teaching school.
      - Letters to Iverson L. Twyman (1849-1921), 1880, n.d., 4 items. (Folder 85)
        W. T. Williams, S. W. Holman (of Mexia, Texas), F. P. Moseley, S. A. Moreland (bears letter of Holman), J. P. Philpott, Bass Williams, letter of recommendation of Twyman signed by citizens of Buckingham.
    - John A. Twyman, 1871-1937, n.d., 383 items. (Folder 86-105)
      - Letters by John A. Twyman, 1871-1906., 10 items. (Folder 86)
        Letters to Iverson L. Twyman bear letters from Samuel R. Twyman and Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, concerning family's poverty and his desire for an education; two people in jail for whipping children to death. Letter (draft) to Joseph Dupuy Eggleston, State Superintendent of Public Instruction, and teachers certificates signed in 1902-1905 by Twyman as Superintendent of Schools, Buckingham County, Va.
      - Letters by John A. Twyman, 1907-1930, n.d., 21 items. (Folder 87)
        Includes copies of letters to Joseph Dupuy Eggleston concerning a controversy over the location of a school; copies of love letters to ""Miss Smith"" in December 1907 - January 1908 and copies of love letters to Josephine White, December 1922 - January 1923.
      - Letters to and about John A. Twyman, 1875-1880., 10 items. (Folder 88)
        Includes letters from William Merry Perkins, N. A. Moseley, J. R. Blackburn, Eben S. Stearns (concerning Twyman's attendence at State Normal School, now Peabody College) and William S. Eldridge. Includes teachers certificates. One letter is to Iverson L. Twyman from John M. Colby concerning sale of Lee's Reminiscences.
      - Letters to and about John A. Twyman, 1881., 17 items. (Folder 89)
        Letters to Twyman in Starrville, Texas concerning State Normal College, Nashville, Tenn. (now Peabody), from Charles W. Bache, E. G. Littlejohn, Jr., J. S. Dobbins.
      - Letters to John A. Twyman, 1882-1899., 7 items. (Folder 90)
        Letters to him in Texas and Virginia. Includes letters from Joseph E. Dobbins, E. G. Maller, J. A. Mundy, E. W. Twyman, [W. M. or Wm.] Cabell. Concern State Normal College, Nashville, Tenn. (now Peabody) and dissension in Mulberry Grove Church, Buckingham County.
      - Letters to John A. Twyman, 1900-1905., 6 items. (Folder 91)
        Includes four letters from Miss Sally M. Smith (see folder 87 for copies of his letters to her) and C. M. [Feigenspan ?].
      - Letters to John A. Twyman, 1906., 17 items. (Folder 92)